- [Instructor] Now the application is growing really fast
with some additional features.
Line four, we have this extra component
that we use to keep track of the score,
so each time that you get the answer right.
And this one is visible right here.
So every time that you get the answer right,
it's going to be incremented by one.
So let's try this one out.
I already have my app up and running.
So we're going to try to add up 31 plus 28
and that should add up to 59.
Let's see if this is right.
Perfect. You guessed right.
And my points is visible right here, my new score.
So the bigger the application,
the more challenging it is to maintain.
Let me show you one quick example.
Right here, we have the Dropbox website,
which is also built with the React library.
Let's have a look inside by using the React dev tools.
You're going to see that this is a very complex application
with multiple levels of deeply nested components
of the application tree right here.
So imagine having to go through hundreds
or thousands of lines of code.
When you need to share the state across the application,
you need to pass the props manually
and it can be very tedious and time consuming
to manage and to maintain.
And you may also need to deal with
many programming concerns, like multiple duplications,
state object in different places,
and where communications between components can only be done
by traversing multiple layers of the application tree.
And so, dealing with the states management
in a React application can be a tricky thing,
and especially when data needs to be passed
from a root component.
So if I need to go all the way to the top,
that's going to take me a long time.
So from the root component and down
deeply nested components,
and it's going to take me a while
to go all the way down as well.
This leads to one recurrent and common concern
called props drilling.
And so, the best way to overcome the pitfall
of props drilling is to keep the state management
structure flat, with the application state
centralized in one single location
so you can easily manage and update it over time.
So the idea behind a single source of truth
is to separate the business logic from the presentation.
This leads to the introduction of the context API,
which is also part of the React API.
With the context API, the state lives in one place
and is accessible everywhere.
Let's discover more about how to manage the state globally
with a single source of truth
with the context API.